Guide to the Janet G. Travell papers, 1910-1997 MS0704.UA
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Papers, manuscripts, reports and subject research, 1930-1994; MS0704 Series 2; 10 Linear feet (Box 26, Box 27, Box 28, Box 29, Box 37, Box 32, Box 18, Box 31, Box 19, Box 30, Box 20, Box 17, Box 21, Box 22, Box 36, Box 23, Box 35, Box 24, Box 34, Box 25, Box 33)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Manuscript "Skeletal Muscle Pain as an Aspect of Metabolic Insufficiency", 1955 ca. (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Manuscript "Skeletal Muscle Pain as an Aspect of the Hypometabolic Syndrome,", 02/18/1957 (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Manuscript on absorption of nicotine, 1959-1960 (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Manuscript on effects of nicotine on the heart, 1960 (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Manuscript on Jaw Pain for Journal of Prosthetic Dentistry, 1960 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Manuscripts - Pain mechanisms, 1952 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Manuscripts - Sacroiliac and gluteus minimus, 1941-1946 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Manuscript "The Myofascial component of Intermittent Claudication", 1953 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Medical Aspects of Seat Design, 1944-1954 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Medical notes on Dr. Willard Travell, 1947-1960 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    Includes one small chest x-ray
  - Reports, Subject Research: Medical Society of the District of Columbia - Physical Fitness Committee, 1972-1975 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Meeting with David Zohn and staff, 07/19/1983 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Meeting with Lawrence A Funt, Bethesda, MD - Endocrine Problems in Myofascial Pain, 06/27/1983 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Mental Retardation Research, 1961-1963 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Metals - Lead, Zinc, Bismuth, 1936-1957 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Metals - Mercury, 1938-1955 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Military Gunner's Control, 1952 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Miscellaneous notes on Shoulder Pain, 1938 (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Morphine Study by Janet Travell, 1924 (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Motor Visceral and Viscero Motor Syndrome, 1954-1958 (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Multicausal etiology, 1957-1958 (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Multiple Uses of Local Block, 1948 (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Muscle & Joint Temperature Measurements, Skin & Vascular Temps., 1945-1959 (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Muscle & Joint Temperature Measurements, Skin & Vascular Temps., 1945-1959 (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Muscle Testing, 1950-1953 (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Muscular and Neuromuscular Responses (General) and muscular analysis, 1939-1949 (Box 24, Folder 22)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Muscular Dystrophy - bibliography, 1960 (Box 24, Folder 23)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Mustard Gas Burns, 1950 (Box 24, Folder 24)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Myalgias of the Abdomen, 1952-1978 (Box 24, Folder 25)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Myasthenia gravis, 1939-1954 (Box 24, Folder 26)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Myofascial Trigger Areas, 1940-1971 (Box 24, Folder 27)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Myotonia, 1949-1957 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Reports, Subject Research: National Jogging Association, 1968-1976 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Nature of trigger areas, 1954-1974 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Nerve Impulse, 1938-1960 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Reports, Subject Research: New York Academy of Sciences (Medicine), 1959 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Reports, Subject Research: New York Heart Association - paper on cardiovascular arm and shoulder pain, 03/24/1952 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Nicotine experiments, 1956-1957 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Nicotine and Pharmacology, 1952-1955 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Nicotine Grantees Symposium, NY, NY, 1957 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Nicotine Perfusions - Memo Sheets, 1956 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Nicotine research, 1950ca. (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Reports, Subject Research: NIH Public Health Service Grant, 1953-1954 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Reports, Subject Research: NIH Public Health Service Grant, 1954-1955 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Noise, 1966-1967 (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Notecards, undated (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Notes on Freon Survey Uses, 1953-1954 (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Osteopathy, 1966-1972 (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Reports, Subject Research: P&P Chair Company, Asheboro, N.C., 1953-1974 (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Pain and Hypometabolism, 1954-1956 (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Pain Theories, 1948-1951 (Box 25, Folder 20)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Pain Threshold Experiments, 1949-1950 (Box 25, Folder 21)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Pain Treatment, 1940-1953 (Box 25, Folder 22)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Painful Scar cases, 1943-1959 (Box 25, Folder 23)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Painless Injection, 1976-1977 (Box 25, Folder 24)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Paper "The Absorption of Nicotine From Various Sites", 1960 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Paper by Janet Travell "Assessment of Drugs for Therapeutic Efficacy", 1954 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Paper by Janet Travell, S.H. Rinzler, and H. Bakst "The Somatic Component of Cardiac Pain,", 1950 ca. (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Paper by Janet Travell, Seymour H. Rinzler, et al "Detection of Coronary Atherosclerosis in the Living Rabbit by the Ergonovine Stress Test,", 1955 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Paper by S.H. Rinzler and H. Bakst on cardiac pain, 1950ca. (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Papers of Dr. Rene Leriche, 1932-1952 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Papers on Shoulder Pain, 1940-1949 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Parasites, 1938-1955 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Passive Stretching and Effects on Muscle, 1937-1959 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Pelvic asymmetry, 1970-1972 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Peripheral Vascular Disease, 1931-1953 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Pharmacological Effects - Cardiac Irritability, 1951-1956 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Photographs of skeletal structure and anatomy of leg, 1957ca. (Box 26, Folder 13)
    Includes one x-ray
  - Reports, Subject Research: Physchosomatic versus somapsychotic disease, 1958 (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Physical Fitness, 1961-1967 (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Pilot's Vertigo, 1957-1959 (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Poliomyelitis, 1949 (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Reports, Subject Research: "Post disc" syndrome, 1950-1953 (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Postural vertigo, 1954-1957 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Potassium, 1938-1942 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Procaine - General Clinical Uses, 1930-1957 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Procaine - General, 1943-1951 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Procaine Amide, 1950-1957 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Procaine and Arthritis, 1940-1952 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Procaine and Cardiac Rhythms, 1940-1946 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Procaine and Fractures, 1943-1949 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Procaine and Low Back Pain, 1940-1945 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Procaine and Shoulder Pain, 1941-1951 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Procaine Assays/Protocols, 1946 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Procaine Clinical Application, 1945-1950 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Procaine Data, 1943-1944 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Procaine Dosage - Study, 1946 (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Procaine Headache, 1944 (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Procaine in Shoulder and Arm Pain - requests for reprints, 1942-1944 (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Procaine Intravenous, 1944-1950 (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Procaine Intravenous, 1945-1950 (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Procaine treatment, 1958-1973 (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Procaine, 1945-1962 (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Procaine, 1946-1961 (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Procaine: A versatile drug, 1968-1975 (Box 27, Folder 22)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Procedure for painless injection, New York Hospital, 1957 (Box 27, Folder 23)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Protein Bound Iodine variations, 1953-1960 (Box 27, Folder 24)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Public Health Service Grant, 1950-1951 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Public Health Service Grant, 1950-1951 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Public Health Service Grant, 1951-1952 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Public Health Service Grant Progress Reports, 1951-1955 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Public Health Service Grant Progress Reports, 1955-1956 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Public Health Service Grant Progress Reports, 1956-1957 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Reports, Subject Research: Public Health Service Grant, 1949-1950 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Public Health Service Grant, 1949-1950 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Public Health Service Grant, 1952-1953 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Pyridoxine - Vitamin B6, 1964-1972 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Quadratus Lumborum muscle - notes, references, 1980-1982 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Quadratus Lumborum Muscle and Low Back Pain, 1976 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Reports, Subject Research: "Rapid Relief of Acute 'Stiff Neck' by Ethyl Chloride Spray" by Janet Travell, 1949 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Reports, Subject Research: References on Iron, 1943-1960 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Reflex Somatovisceral effects - cold stimulus, 1950-1965 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Reports on work and publications of Janet Travell, 1933-1955 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Reports on work and publications of Janet Travell, 1933-1955 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Research assistant search, 1957 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Retinal Changes and Hypertension, 1940ca. (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Sacroiliac data, 1945 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Sacroiliac Joint, 1936-1966 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Sacroiliac-Sciatica, 1942-1946 (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Sciatica - Restless legs, 1943 (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Scurvy, 1970-1971 (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Short-leg syndrome, 1962-1972 (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Shoulder and Arm Pain, 1930-1958 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Shoulder Pain after Myocardial Infarction, 1940-1954 (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Shoulder Pain manuscript drafts and notes, 1940-1941 (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Shoulder Pain, 1958-1959 (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Skeletal Muscle Pain, Bellevue, 03/10/1955 (Box 29, Folder 19)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Skin & Muscle Temperature - notes and references, 1953-1954 (Box 29, Folder 20)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Skin and Muscle Temperature Experiments on Speedomax, 1953 (Box 29, Folder 21)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Skin and Muscle Temperature Experiments on Speedomax, 1953 (Box 29, Folder 22)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Skin and Muscle Temperatures - Laboratory Data from Speedomax, 1954 (Box 29, Folder 23)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Skin resistance - correspondence, 1953 (Box 29, Folder 24)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Skin Temperature studies, 1951 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Somatic Component Of Hysteria - Case Reports, 1940ca. (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Somatic pain syndromes of the chest, 1942-1948 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Special Mixtures, Skin Tests, 1955 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Special Research Project: Wenger Neonatal Respiratory Problems, 1963 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Sprains - Case Reports, 1940 ca. (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Spray and histamine experiments, 1949 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Standing, 1940-1972 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Sternomastoid Syndrome cases, 1954-1960 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Stiff Neck/Whip Lash, 1952-1973 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Stress Adaptation, 1959 (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Students referred by Dr. Perkins - Cholesterol study, 1958 (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Submission of paper "Detection of Coronary Atherosclerosis in the Living Rabbit by the Ergonovine Stress Test," to American Journal of Physiology magazine, 1955 (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Sunburn study - PABA Experiments, 1950 (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Swimming, 1958-1973 (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Sympathetics, 1952-1959 (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - Reports, Subject Research: "Technic for Reduction and Ambulatory Treatment of Sacroiliac Displacement" - paper by Willard Travell (Dr. Travell's father) and Janet Travell, 1941 (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - Reports, Subject Research: "Technic for Reduction & Ambulatory Treatment of Sacroiliac Displacement," by Janet Travell, undated (Box 30, Folder 18)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Tetanus, 1959-1960 (Box 30, Folder 19)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Tetracaine Hydrochloride, 1951-1954 (Box 30, Folder 20)
  - Reports, Subject Research: The Ear and Audiometry, 1949-1950 (Box 30, Folder 21)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Thermal Burns in Fowls - experiment notes, 1954 (Box 30, Folder 22)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Thiamine Methodology, 1960-1969 (Box 30, Folder 23)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Thiamine -Vitamin B1, 1961-1971 (Box 30, Folder 24)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Thyroid-Hypothyroid-Hypothyroidism, 1959 (Box 30, Folder 25)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Tobacco and Smoking, 1972-1986 (Box 30, Folder 26)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Tobacco as food, 1977-1982 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Toe Stand Test, 1951 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Treadlometer design notes, 1947-1952 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Trichinosis Creatine Study, 1952 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Trigger Point terminology, 1926-1994 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Turtle Headache (JAMA), 1963 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Ultrasonic Therapy, 1952-1953 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Ultra-Violet Radiation Burns - experiment notes and data, 1950-1952 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Unpublished manuscript "Temporomandibular Joint Pain Referred from Muscles of the Neck and Head,", 1960 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Vapocoolant Sprays - Freon, 1948-1950 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Vapocoolant spray - correspondence, 1959 (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Vertigo, 1955-1971 (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Skin and Muscle Temperature Experiments on Speedomax, 1953 (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Veterans Administration grant project with David Simons, 1968-1970 (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Virginia Weeks' Experiments on Skin Temperature, 1954 (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Vitamin B1 in Hypothyroidism - Case Report, 1940 ca. (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Vitamin B12, 1959-1972 (Box 31, Folder 17)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Vitamin D, 1970-1971 (Box 31, Folder 18)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Vitamin E data analysis, 1947-1953 (Box 31, Folder 19)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Vitamin E, 1945-1971 (Box 31, Folder 20)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Vitamin E experiments, 1941-1950 (Box 31, Folder 21)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Vitamin H (Biotin), 1945-1970 (Box 31, Folder 22)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Weather, 1954-1959 (Box 31, Folder 23)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Weber-Christian Disease, undated (Box 31, Folder 24)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Wheelchairs, 1972-1976 (Box 31, Folder 25)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Wyeth Laboratories Grant Application and Correspondence, 1953-1954 (Box 31, Folder 26)
  - Reports, Subject Research: X-Ray therapy and Chest Pain, 1947-1949 (Box 31, Folder 27)
  - Patient chart, 1942-1948 (Box 31, Folder 28)
    Names and addresses have been deleted from record
  - Patient chart, 1943-1947 (Box 31, Folder 29)
  - Patient chart, 1943-1949 (Box 31, Folder 30)
  - Patient chart, 1944-1952 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Patient chart, 1945 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Patient chart, 1945-1946 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Patient chart, 1945-1947 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Patient chart, 1945-1951 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Patient chart, 1945-1960 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Patient chart: Patient file, 1945-1970 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Patient chart, 1946 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Patient chart, 1946-1947 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Patient chart, 1946-1947 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Patient chart, 1947 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Patient chart, 1947-1958 (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Patient chart, 1948 (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Patient chart, 1948 (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - Patient chart, 1948-1959 (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - Patient chart, 1950 (Box 32, Folder 16)
  - Patient chart, 1950-1959 (Box 32, Folder 17)
  - Patient chart, 1950-1960 (Box 32, Folder 18)
  - Patient chart, 1951-1960 (Box 32, Folder 19)
  - Patient chart, 1953-1960 (Box 32, Folder 20)
  - Patient chart, 1953-1960 (Box 32, Folder 21)
  - Patient chart, 1953-1961 (Box 32, Folder 22)
  - Patient chart, 1955-1958 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Patient chart, 1957-1960 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Patient chart, 1958 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Patient chart, 1958-1960 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Patient chart, 1958-1959 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Patient chart, 1959 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Patient chart, 1959 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Patient chart, 1960 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Patient chart, 1960 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Patient chart, 1963 (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Patient chart, 1978 (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Patient chart: Patient files and correspondence, 1965-1982 (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Patient chart: Correspondence and patient charts, 1951-1960 (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - Patient chart: Patient charts and correspondence, 1976-1979 (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - Patient chart: Unequal leg lengths, 1945-1960 (Box 33, Folder 15)
  - Patient chart: Unequal leg lengths, 1957-1962 (Box 33, Folder 16)
  - Patient chart: Unequal leg lengths, 1958 (Box 33, Folder 17)
  - Patient chart: Unequal leg lengths, 1960 (Box 33, Folder 18)
  - Patient chart: Unequal leg lengths, 1960 (Box 33, Folder 19)
  - Patient chart: Patient file and correspondence, 1976-1990 (Box 33, Folder 20)
  - Seat and Chair Design: Airline seat design, 1952-1956 (Box 33, Folder 21)
    With full scale mechanical drawings
  - Seat and Chair Design: American Airlines Compartment Interior, 1956 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Seat and Chair Design: Automobile Seating, 1955-1958 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Seat and Chair Design: Bicycle Design Report, 1952 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Seat and Chair Design: Bicycle design, 1952 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Seat and Chair Design: Bicycle design, 1952-1953 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Seat and Chair Design: Chair design, 1953-1966 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Seat and Chair Design: Civil Aeronautical Authority air tower design, 1954 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Seat and Chair Design: Consolidated Vultee Aircraft Corporation - correspondence with Henry Dreyfuss, 1944-1945 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Seat and Chair Design: Consolidated Vultee Aircraft Corporation - seat design, 1946-1948 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Seat and Chair Design: Correspondence on chair design, 1944-1946 (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Seat and Chair Design: Correspondence regarding seat design, 1955-1959 (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Seat and Chair Design: Correspondence relating to posture and seating design (and other), 1957-1986 (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Seat and Chair Design: Furniture and Seating Design, 1951-1961 (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - Seat and Chair Design: Hyster truck seat design, 1958 (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - Seat and Chair Design: John Deere & Co. Seat design, 1945-1980 (Box 34, Folder 15)
  - Seat and Chair Design: Lockheed seating, 1955 (Box 34, Folder 16)
  - Seat and Chair Design: Lockheed seating report, 1955-1956 (Box 34, Folder 17)
    See also Box 78: folder 4
  - Seat and Chair Design: Manuscript "Importance of Sitting Comfortably", 1956 (Box 34, Folder 18)
  - Seat and Chair Design: Manuscript on Conference Chairs, 1956 (Box 34, Folder 19)
  - Seat and Chair Design: Manuscripts on seat design by Dr. Travell, 1951-1952 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Seat and Chair Design: Mechanical drawings for seating design, 1952 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    Large drawing removed to oversize material in Series VII: Box 104
  - Seat and Chair Design: Notes on bicycle seat design, 1952 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Seat and Chair Design: Operator's chair design for AT&T, 1946 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Seat and Chair Design: Photographs of chair design for the body, undated (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Seat and Chair Design: Report on seat design of "Electra Seat" for Lockheed, 1955-1956 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Seat and Chair Design: Reports on aircraft and tractor seat design - Dreyfuss and Travell, 1954-1955 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    See also Box 43: folder 9
  - Seat and Chair Design: Rocking chairs, 1946-1964 (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Seat and Chair Design: Seat and Chair Design, 1949-1976 (Box 35, Folder 9)
    See also Box 79: folder 9
  - Seat and Chair Design: Seating Design References, 1952-1958 (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Seat and Chair Design: Seating -Household, 1961-1969 (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - Seat and Chair Design: Singer sewing machine chair design, 1960 (Box 35, Folder 12)
    With full scale mechanical drawing
  - Seat and Chair Design: Toilet seat design, 1947-1955 (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - Seat and Chair Design: Wolf Trap Theater Seats, 1969-1972 (Box 35, Folder 14)
  - Ethyl Chloride Spray: Acute Myocardial Infarction - ethyl chloride spray, 1941 (Box 35, Folder 15)
  - Ethyl Chloride Spray: Article and correspondence on ethyl chloride spray in Pageant magazine, 1953 (Box 35, Folder 16)
  - Ethyl Chloride Spray: Article for Circulation magazine by Janet Travell on relief of chest pain by ethyl chloride spray, 1950 (Box 36, Folder 1)